<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Workflow on Damian Galarza | Technical Partner for Startups &amp; Fractional CTO</title><link>https://damiangalarza.com/tags/workflow/</link><description>Recent content in Workflow on Damian Galarza | Technical Partner for Startups &amp; Fractional CTO</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://damiangalarza.com/tags/workflow/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Understanding Claude Code's Context Window</title><link>https://damiangalarza.com/posts/2025-12-08-understanding-claude-code-context-window/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://damiangalarza.com/posts/2025-12-08-understanding-claude-code-context-window/</guid><description>A look at how Claude Code&amp;rsquo;s context window works, what uses tokens, and how to manage it effectively with subagents, skills, and the /context command.</description></item><item><title>Code review with Claude Code</title><link>https://damiangalarza.com/posts/2025-11-26-claude-code-review/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://damiangalarza.com/posts/2025-11-26-claude-code-review/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;In my previous post &lt;a href="https://damiangalarza.com/posts/2025-11-25-how-i-use-claude-code/"&gt;How I Use Claude Code: My Complete Development Workflow&lt;/a&gt; I walked through my typical workflow which includes a step that has Claude perform some code reviews of it&amp;rsquo;s own work. I want to take some time to explore this a little further. The first time I heard someone suggest to have Claude review it&amp;rsquo;s own work I was confused. How could having the same thing that generated this code be helpful in reviewing it? The first time I did it though I was blown away. I gave it some concepts to look out for, reviewed the code myself first to see what I would want to change and made a mental note of it. From there I instructed Claude to review it&amp;rsquo;s work with an eye for a few specific concepts and it came back with a thorough report of changes that were in line with my vision.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>How I Use Claude Code: My Complete Development Workflow</title><link>https://damiangalarza.com/posts/2025-11-25-how-i-use-claude-code/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://damiangalarza.com/posts/2025-11-25-how-i-use-claude-code/</guid><description>A deep dive into my daily Claude Code workflow, covering how I leverage the CLI tool for code exploration, implementation, refactoring, and debugging. Learn practical patterns that boost development productivity.</description></item></channel></rss>