<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Product-Strategy on Damian Galarza | Technical Partner for Startups &amp; Fractional CTO</title><link>https://damiangalarza.com/tags/product-strategy/</link><description>Recent content in Product-Strategy on Damian Galarza | Technical Partner for Startups &amp; Fractional CTO</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 10 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://damiangalarza.com/tags/product-strategy/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Startup Software in a Regulated World — Without Slowing Down</title><link>https://damiangalarza.com/posts/2025-07-10-building-compliant-startup-software/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://damiangalarza.com/posts/2025-07-10-building-compliant-startup-software/</guid><description>We built the internal platform that powered Join Parachute’s first plasma collection center and scaled it to 26+ FDA-licensed sites. This post shares how we delivered under tight timelines, aligned with regulatory requirements, and laid the groundwork for our first FDA-cleared SaMD — all while maintaining startup speed.</description></item><item><title>The Double-Edged Sword of Customer Obsession</title><link>https://damiangalarza.com/posts/2025-07-02-balancing-customer-obsession/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://damiangalarza.com/posts/2025-07-02-balancing-customer-obsession/</guid><description>Customer obsession is a powerful value—but when taken too far, it can lead to burnout, reactive teams, and a fragmented product. This post explores how to apply it with balance, strategy, and respect for your team.</description></item><item><title>The AI Prompt I Wish I Had While Documenting SaMD Systems in Rails</title><link>https://damiangalarza.com/posts/2025-06-22-generate-sds-docs-samd-ai/</link><pubDate>Sat, 21 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://damiangalarza.com/posts/2025-06-22-generate-sds-docs-samd-ai/</guid><description>&lt;p>At Buoy Software, I led the design and development of our first &lt;strong>Software as a Medical Device (SaMD)&lt;/strong>, which was my first experience operating within an FDA-regulated environment. It was a great learning experience, but it came with a lot of heavy documentation. One of the most time-consuming parts was compiling the Design History File (DHF) — the set of artifacts that describe how the system was built and tested. A central piece of that file is the Software Design Specification (SDS), which describes the behavior, design, and rationale for each component in the system.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>